<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Samir's blog</title>
    <description>Hello. You are welcome to my blog. Trying to find my way in software development, mathematics and life. Feed free to enjoy some of my toughts.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 23:57:26 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 23:57:26 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Beggining of writing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Thr pen is mightier than the sword.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve had the intent to start writing for some time now, but never got to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the first articles where half written quite some time ago. Main reasons
for staring this blog are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learn to write better and express myself better. Having good grammar and ability 
  to express yourself is a valuable skill as for personal and career opportunities. 
  Dijkstra even went as far as to state that a good programmer has to have a 
  nice handwriting. The silent people like myself have to cope with it somehow.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Learn to reason better and explain my ideas and arguments more axiomatically.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Indulge into the community of programmers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Note some interesting stuff so I don’t want forget it myself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As i’ve taken the challenge of writing, I hope to make a scientific paper 
by the end of the academic year, so my first topic will be reading as many 
papers as I can and write a short summary on them here.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/Begining-of-writing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/Begining-of-writing.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>posts</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fibbonacci(n) - part 1</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Test&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fibonnacci is so old, I dont have to write anything on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex; mode=display&quot;&gt;a^2 + b^2 = c^2&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what should we do about it?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/Its-so-old.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/Its-so-old.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>posts</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
